I know everyone wants me to say "Devil Wears Prada" line because it's the one that's quoted to me most.
我知道大家都希望我说《穿普拉达的女王》里的台词，因为这是别人引用我最多的一句。
Clearly the one that's quoted to me most will be a "Devil Wears Prada" line.
显然，被引用最多的一定会是《穿普拉达的女王》里的台词。
Something about cheese.
关于奶酪的某一句。
Exactly. Something about cheese.
没错，就是关于奶酪的那句。
Emily, what is the one activity you do every day?
Emily，你每天都会做的一件事情是什么？
I wish I did transcendental meditation every day.
我希望自己每天都做超验冥想。
I don't do it every day.
我不是每天都做。
I do eat dark chocolate every day, so I'm gonna do that.
不过我的确每天都会吃黑巧克力，所以我就说这个吧。
—In high school, you turn out a pop record contract? —Yes.
—高中时期，你拒绝了一份流行音乐唱片合约？—是的。
Who is the one collaborator that could take you out of your pop retirement?
哪一位合作对象能够让你结束流行音乐隐退状态？
Can he just prize me out of this pop reclusivity?
他能不能把我从这种流行音乐隐居状态中"请出来"？
I think if anyone can, it's Lin.
我觉得如果有人能做到，那就是 Lin。
Is there one song of his that you wish you collaborated with him on?
有没有他的某首歌，是你希望曾经和他合作的？
Well, my kids always say I'm not allowed to play it, but it's "Dear Theodosia" 'cause it's just the most beautiful lullaby on earth.
我的孩子总说不允许我播放这首歌，但它是《Dear Theodosia》，因为它简直是世界上最美的摇篮曲。
Every time I play it in the car, the kids are like, "It's too sad."
每次我在车里播放它，孩子们都会说："太悲伤了。"
It's devastating.
它太令人心碎了。
What is the one relationship that taught you the most about who you are?
哪一段关系让你最了解自己？
Sorry, John Krasinski, but it is our children.
抱歉，John Krasinski，但答案是我们的孩子。
Because you do go through this complete awakening when you have kids.
因为当你有孩子后，你确实会经历一次彻底的觉醒。
I know any parent will attest.
我知道任何父母都会证明这一点。
The challenge of it, the beauty of it, that's sort of reclamation of maybe who you really are.
其中的挑战、其中的美好，这是一种重新找回真实自我的过程。
And how I don't think anybody sees you as purely as your children do.
我觉得没有任何人像你的孩子一样纯粹地看待你。
Or bringing you back to earth like they do.
或者像他们一样把你拉回现实。
I find that like the most kaleidoscopic experience of my life.
我觉得那是我人生中最丰富多彩、变化万千的经历。
What is the one parenting hot take you stand by?
你坚持的一个育儿"另类观点"是什么？
Bribery. Isn't that half of parenting?
贿赂。这不就是育儿的一半吗？
What do you bribe them with?
你用什么来贿赂他们？
I mean, definitely, their love of dark chocolate is matched with my own.
我的意思是，我们都很喜欢吃黑巧克力。
If you eat another piece of broccoli, you could get another square of chocolate.
如果你再吃一块西兰花，你就能得到另一小块巧克力。
What is the one quality you look for in a mom friend?
你在妈妈朋友身上寻找的一个品质是什么？
I have friends where there's just this secret language of understanding.
我有一些朋友，我们之间有一种无需言说的理解方式。
And yeah, I look for that.
是的，我会寻找这种感觉。
That sort of effortless secret language that you have with some other moms that just get it in every way.
那种你和一些妈妈之间拥有的毫不费力的默契，她们在各个方面都能理解你。
Not just moms, just friends in general.
不只是妈妈朋友，普通朋友也是如此。
Your husband, John Krasinski, directed "A Quiet Place" which you also starred in.
你的丈夫 John Krasinski 导演了《寂静之地》，而你也出演了这部电影。
What is the one drive to or from work that you'll never forget?
哪一次上下班路上的车程是你永远不会忘记的？
I think he will never forget the first day when I'd left it rather till the last minute to go, "Do you know how to shoot a film?"
我觉得他永远不会忘记第一天，那天我拖到最后一刻才问："你知道怎么拍电影吗？"
Because I don't know how to shoot a film, so I'm just wondering if you know what you're doing.
因为我不知道怎么拍电影，所以我只是想确认一下，你知道自己在做什么吗。
And then actually the drive home was clearly like I'd had an awakening.
然后实际上回家的那段路，就像我经历了一次觉醒。
Seeing that this person who I thought I knew everything about had this sort of secret power.
看到这个我以为自己完全了解的人，竟然拥有这种隐藏的能力。
It was really amazing seeing this whole other superpower that he had that I don't think he even knew what he was capable of doing.
看到他拥有另一种我觉得甚至连他自己都不知道的超能力，真的非常神奇。
What's the one movie you can quote embarrassingly well?
哪部电影是你能熟练背出台词，甚至有点尴尬地熟练？
It's only because I just showed it to my kids recently.
只是因为我最近刚给孩子们看了这部电影。
I love that bit. She's so brilliant, isn't it?
我喜欢那一段。
What is the one audition that changed the trajectory of your career?
哪一次试镜改变了你的职业轨迹？
It would have to be for "The Devil Wears Prada."
那一定是《穿普拉达的女王》。
I was 22 and I was actually auditioning at Fox Studios for another movie that thank God I didn't get.
我22岁的时候，实际上正在福克斯影业为另一部电影试镜，谢天谢地我没有得到那个角色。
And they said, "Hey, while you are here, do you want to audition for "The Devil Wears Prada"?
然后他们说："嘿，既然你在这里，要不要试镜《穿普拉达的女王》？"
And that changed my life completely in every way.
那完全改变了我的人生，各个方面都是。
And now you're returning to "The Devil Wears Prada."
现在你又回到了《穿普拉达的女王》。
Years later.
多年以后。
Am I having a hallucination?
我是在产生幻觉吗？
We were at runway at the same time, Miranda.
我们当时都在 Runway 杂志工作，Miranda。
What is the one shift in dynamics on set that's been the most fun to experience?
片场关系变化中，最有趣的变化是什么？
Maybe we're just even less tolerant of wearing high heels all day.
可能只是我们现在更不能忍受整天穿高跟鞋了。
Maybe we just complain more.
可能只是我们抱怨更多了。
I know 20 years has gone by.
我知道20年已经过去了。
But it felt like a blink.
但感觉就像眨眼之间。
It felt like nothing and so much has happened in between.
感觉像什么都没发生，但中间又发生了那么多事。
Stanley Tucci is now my brother-in-law and we are family in every single way.
Stanley Tucci现在是我的姐夫/妹夫，我们在各个意义上都是一家人。
He would've been my chosen family and now he actually is my family.
他本来就会是我选择的家人，而现在他实际上真的成为了我的家人。
Does that show up on set?
这种关系会不会体现在片场？
Yeah, he told me that I was shameless most of the time with some of my comedy choices.
是的，他告诉我，我很多时候在喜剧表演选择上简直"毫无羞耻"。
They would call "Cut" and he'd just go, "Oh shameless."
他们会喊"停"，然后他就会说："哦，真是不要脸。"
What is the one piece of advice from Meryl Streep that you still hear in your head?
Meryl Streep给过你的哪一条建议，你至今仍然记在脑海里？
She doesn't give out advice.
她不会主动给别人建议。
She doesn't feel like she wants to impart wisdom on you.
她不会觉得自己想要向你传授什么人生智慧。
She wants to be one of the peeps, you know?
她只是想成为大家中的一员。
I would love her to give me advice.
我当然希望她能给我建议。
I don't think she would presume to.
但我觉得她不会自认为有资格这样做。
What is the one line from your career that you find most iconic?
你职业生涯中，你认为最具代表性的一句台词是什么？
I know everyone wants me to say a "Devil Wears Prada" line because it's the one that's quoted to me most.
我知道大家都希望我说一句《穿普拉达的女王》的台词，因为这是别人引用我最多的。
But there's a moment in "Oppenheimer" where Kitty Oppenheimer has been obviously drinking heavily and just deteriorating as a character.
但是《奥本海默》中有一个片段，Kitty Oppenheimer 明显大量饮酒，作为角色也逐渐崩坏。
And becoming more volatile and unreliable.
并且变得更加情绪不稳定、无法预测。
And no one wants her to testify.
没有人希望她出庭作证。
And so the odds are kind of stacked against her and she's super wobbly.
所以形势对她非常不利，她的状态也非常不稳定。
And then she just finally gathers it and she goes, "Well, it was also very long ago, Mr. Rob, wasn't it?"
然后她终于重新振作起来，说："不过，那也是很久以前的事了，对吧，Rob先生？"
Long enough to have forgotten and she kind of comes back to life.
久到足以让人忘记，而她也仿佛重新活了过来。
Even on the day, I remember Chris Nolan saying, "Don't be afraid to just stick that landing with that line."
甚至在拍摄当天，我记得 Chris Nolan 说："不要害怕把那句台词完美落地。"
Like don't be afraid of it just being a real moment.
就是说，不要害怕让它成为一个真实的瞬间。
Clearly the one that's quoted to me most will be a "Devil Wears Prada" line.
显然，别人引用最多的还是《穿普拉达的女王》的台词。
You are in Steven Spielberg's new sci-fi movie "Disclosure Day."
你出演 Steven Spielberg 的新科幻电影《Disclosure Day》。
Whatever happens, don't you let it go.
无论发生什么，都不要放手。
What's the one surprise on Spielberg sets?
在 Spielberg 的片场，最大的惊喜是什么？
How fun it was.
它有多么有趣。
He is so available as a person.
作为一个人，他非常容易接近。
Even if you want to dork out and ask him endless stories about "ET" or "Indiana Jones."
即使你想像个影迷一样兴奋地问他关于《ET》或《夺宝奇兵》的各种故事。
He's just available and joyous and buoyant to be around.
他就是那么容易接近，而且待在他身边会让人感到快乐、有活力。
I was really amazed by the spontaneity of him.
他的自发性真的让我非常惊讶。
He doesn't pre-plan anything.
他不会提前计划任何事情。
Nothing's mapped out.
没有任何东西被提前规划好。
He gets there, he feels it, and he's just...
他到了现场，感受当下，然后……
It was such a vibrant experience watching him work.
看他工作是一种非常充满活力的体验。
You see why he's the greatest of all time.
你就明白为什么他是历史最佳。
Yet he doesn't wear that like as his front foot.
然而，他并不会把这些成就摆在最前面。
He's just a kid wanting to tell stories and wanting to bring you into the fold of it in every way.
他只是一个想讲故事的人，并希望用各种方式让你参与其中。
We were kind of bereft when that film ended.
电影结束时，我们都有点失落。
I felt like I needed to stare at a wall for a day.
我感觉自己需要盯着墙发一天呆。
What is the one red flag you never ignore professionally or personally?
无论在职业还是个人生活中，你绝不会忽视的一个危险信号是什么？
Bad manners.
没礼貌。
Also, your instinct on someone.
还有，就是你对某个人的直觉。
If something stinks, it's 'cause it stinks.
如果某件事闻起来不对劲，那它就是不对劲。
I used to try to sort of get past that first instinct.
过去我总是试图忽略最初的那种直觉。
If you felt a bit wobbly about someone or about a project, I'd always be like, "No, no, it'll be fine. I'm sure it'll be fine."
如果你对某个人或者某个项目感觉有点不安，我以前总会告诉自己："不会不会，没事的，我确定会没事。"
I think you have to listen to that 'cause it's so loud if you listen to it.
我觉得你必须倾听这种感觉，因为如果你真的去听，它其实非常强烈。
What is the one insight you'd give your younger self?
如果可以，你会给年轻时的自己什么建议？
Don't sweat the small stuff.
不要为小事烦恼。
If you're not losing sleep over it, don't worry about it.
如果这件事都没有严重到让你失眠，那就不要担心。